Ben Vineyard

Principal Software Engineer

Las Vegas, NV ben.vineyard@gmail.com 702.913.6903

I have been developing software professionally for over 20 years. I am passionate about what I do, confident I can deliver a viable customer product, and skilled enough to make it fly.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Principal Software Engineer

Kaseya - Henderson, NV June 2018 to Present

- Supporting and enhancing our flagship product which has a mixture of old classic asp, asp.net, asp.net core, and .net core.
- Researching and prototyping how Golang could be used to replace some of our web services and c
 ++ flagship product agents.
- Worked with a team to introduce a new software management enhancement in our flagship using powershell and .net core.

Lead Software Developer

Station Casinos - Las Vegas, NV May 2016 to June 2018

- Lead Agile teams developing software on the MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angularls, Nodels) stack.
- Existing software was ported from .NET.
- All nodeJs sofware was written in Typescript.

Founder/CTO

Botvana - Las Vegas, NV September 2013 to February 2016

- Worked on mobile applications for the iOS platform.
- Worked with Orbinary to upgrade Trinchero Family Estates' current internal Silverlight application.
 Upgrades included a new user interface & migration away from an offline mode in the application.
 The following technologies were leveraged: .Net Framework, C#, WCF, LINQ, MS SQL Server 2008
 R2, SSRS, MVP Passive View pattern
- Created search engine optimized, Wordpress-based websites for clients of SEO For Lawyers.

Sr. Software Engineer III

IGT

September 2011 to July 2014

I wrote software and provided technical leadership for a team of engineers in both the United States and China for the following products under IGT's Advantage Suite:

- IGT Rebates & Commissions (IRC) allows casino users to effectively incentivize, manage and develop
 critical extensions of junket and personal programs. Flexible program configuration options and
 detailed tracking of turnover and loss combine to provide more accurate calculation of commissions
 and rebate awards.
- Technology: .NET Framework, C#, WCF, LINQ, WWF, MS SQL Server 2008 R2, SSRS, MVP Passive View pattern
- The Cage & Table Accounting system automates most of the arduous tasks on a Casino floor. Process table play information, markers, front money, chips, checks, foreign currency exchanges and inventories easily and quickly with a user-friendly, touch screen interface.
- Technology: .NET Framework, C#, Visual C++, MFC, WCF, MS SQL Server 2008 R2, SSRS
- The SAM (Staff Allocation Management) Product is for Systems R&D team leaders at IGT who need to manage their staff allocation and team sheets. The SAM is a web based application that provides real-time User Interfaces & MS Excel views that will provide staff allocation management easy.
- Technology: HTML5/Javascript using jquery, jquery-ui, jqGrid, twitter's bootstrap, node.js, express, mysql

Sr. Software Engineer

The Cosmopolitan of Las Vegas - Las Vegas, NV July 2010 to September 2011

- Architected & developed a queuing infrastructure for OpenTable vendor system, so that it could integrate from their SQL 2008 based database to both our hotel registration system and master data management system (DataFlux).
- Leveraged Microsoft SQL Service Broker for queuing base.
- Leveraged CLR (.NET Common Language Runtime) stored procedures to handle the web service calls between SQL 2008 and the service endpoints. The CLR codebase was C#.
- Architected & developed a solution integrating Microsoft's MSMQ into our SAS data warehouse.
- Architected & developed a high-transactional queuing solution with our IGT gaming machines using C# and WCF.
- Designed and authored an ASP.NET MVC 3 web application for marketing which performed gaming player analytics.

Sr. Software Developer

Advanced Information Systems - Las Vegas, NV February 2010 to July 2010

- Supported and maintained existing ASP.NET & Silverlight web applications with C# managed codebase.
- Architected & developed a cross-site casino progressive system using WCF 4.0 for message transport, Silverlight 4.0 for the user interface, and SQL 2008 for the data store.
- Wrote all managed code in C#.
- Maintained and tested applications via the software development lifecycle.

- · Performed peer code reviews with other developers prior to moving software to QA.
- Architected, developed, and maintained software builds using Microsoft Team Foundation Server.

.NET Software Developer

Tech Results - Las Vegas, NV April 2009 to December 2009

- Designed and implemented both WCF services and the interfaces to consume them.
- Designed and implemented SQL 2000/2005 database schema design and stored procedure interfaces.
- Designed and authored Silverlight 3.0 web application with WCF back-end.
- Supported and maintained existing web application software comprised of ASP.NET front-ends and WCF back-ends.
- Supported and maintained existing SSIS packages.
- Wrote all managed code in C#.
- Maintained and tested applications via the software development life-cycle.

Programmer/Analyst

Station Casinos - Las Vegas, NV May 2005 to April 2009

- Designed and wrote web and pc applications in VB6, VB.NET, & C#.
- Designed and implemented .NET based service plug-ins in a Service Oriented Architecture (SOA).
- Designed and implemented C# web services and WCF services, exposing customer data on an AS400 IBM mainframe.
- Designed and implemented SQL 2000/2005 database interfaces.
- Maintained and tested applications via the software development lifecycle.

Programmer

Silver State Schools Credit Union - Las Vegas, NV August 2003 to May 2005

- Maintained & serviced an ASP/COM based online banking system.
- Co-Authored and maintained a VB.NET implementation of the aforementioned online banking system, written from the ground up.
- Co-Authored and maintained a PHP port of the .NET version of the online system.
- Co-Authored and maintained the company's web-based intranet.

System Engineer/Programmer

Capco Enterprises Inc. - Las Vegas, NV December 2001 to August 2003

- Designed user interface for Player Rewards kiosk prototype, originally targeted for Mandalay Bay Casino, using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator.
- Created the web application for the kiosk prototype using a PHP based frontend and MySQL database backend.
- Engineered the Linux based environment that the prototype operated in.

Web Developer/Designer

Etronixx - Greensboro, NC June 1998 to December 2001

Created basic informational websites utilizing HTML/DHTML/XHTML.

• Created web applications using classic ASP and PHP

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science

University of North Carolina at Greensboro - Henderson, NV August 1997 to May 2001

Skills

c# (10+ years), SQL (10+ years), nodeJs (4 years), asp.net (10+ years)

Links

http://linkedin.com/in/benvineyard

http://www.benvineyard.com

http://www.github.com/benvineyard

Certifications/Licenses

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

March 2013 to Present